<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jack Orcherton</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/</link><description>The personal site for Jack Orcherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 15:06:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackorcherton.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NahamCon CTF</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/nahamcon2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 15:06:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/nahamcon2022/</guid><description>NahamCon 2022 NahamCon was held this weekend, and as a team of three, we reached 242nd place.
Below will provide a walkthrough of the challenges that I solved.
Warm-Up Challenges Exit Vim In this challenge, you connected to a machine by SSH and entered the Vim editor. To solve this challenge, you could use ESC, then &amp;lsquo;:q!&amp;rsquo;.
Keeber Keeber was a set of OSINT challenges.
Challenge 1 A new company keeber has set up a site, discover the domain and author.</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn Nine-Nine Walkthrough</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/thm-brooklynninenine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 15:06:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/thm-brooklynninenine/</guid><description>Brooklyn Nine-Nine Room This is a brief walkthrough to the Brooklyn Nine-Nine Room on TryHackMe
Enumeration Nmap 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 root@ip-10-10-184-59:~# nmap -sV 10.10.9.108 Starting Nmap 7.60 ( https://nmap.org ) at 2022-04-23 00:07 BST Nmap scan report for ip-10-10-9-108.eu-west-1.compute.internal (10.10.9.108) Host is up (0.00098s latency). Not shown: 997 closed ports PORT STATE SERVICE VERSION 21/tcp open ftp vsftpd 3.</description></item><item><title>RootMe Walkthrough</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/thm-rootme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 14:50:28 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/thm-rootme/</guid><description>One of the best ways to learn ethical hacking is to practice it. So below is a walkthrough of the RootMe Room on THM
Reconnaissance Nmap As with most machines, I began with an Nmap scan - which answers the first few questions.
I firstly scanned with sV to determine the software versions, however as the target wouldn&amp;rsquo;t respond to host discovery, I had to disable it using the -Pn option.</description></item><item><title>Learning Ethical Hacking</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/learn-eh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:45:40 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/learn-eh/</guid><description>In this part I hope to discuss the key elements/places to learn ethical hacking.
Prerequisites As hacking is such a large area, this largely depends on the area you wish to advance your career in, but a good place to start is:
Linux Commands - as hacking typically involves using Kali Linux as a virtual machine and you normally have to exploit Linux based commands; you must be confident with the CLI.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Hello and welcome to my new website, I hope to use it as an online CV and a place to talk about cybersecurity and ethical hacking/university related topics.
1 print(&amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;) Due to this, I ask that you ensure that if you follow any of my posts related to hacking you are doing it on your own equipment or equipment that you have prior permission to hack.
All activities I complete are legal under UK law (as long as you follow the above paragraph), however I am not a lawyer and hence accept no responsibility for anything you do!</description></item></channel></rss>