<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jack Orcherton</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/</link><description>The personal site for Jack Orcherton</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 14:50:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackorcherton.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RootMe Walkthrough</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/thm-rootme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 14:50:28 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Jack Orcherton</dc:creator><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/thm-rootme/</guid><description>One of the best ways to learn ethical hacking is to practice it. So below is a walkthrough of the RootMe Room on THM
Reconnaissance Nmap As with most machines, I began with an Nmap scan - which answers the first few questions.
I firstly scanned with sV to determine the software versions, however as the target wouldn&amp;rsquo;t respond to host discovery, I had to disable it using the -Pn option.</description></item><item><title>Learning Ethical Hacking</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/learn-eh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:45:40 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Jack Orcherton</dc:creator><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/learn-eh/</guid><description>In this part I hope to discuss the key elements/places to learn ethical hacking.
Prerequisites As hacking is such a large area, this largely depends on the area you wish to advance your career in, but a good place to start is:
Linux Commands - as hacking typically involves using Kali Linux as a virtual machine and you normally have to exploit Linux based commands; you must be confident with the CLI.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://jackorcherton.github.io/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:01 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>Jack Orcherton</dc:creator><guid>https://jackorcherton.github.io/welcome/</guid><description>Hello and welcome to my new website, I hope to use it as an online CV and a place to talk about cybersecurity and ethical hacking/university related topics.
1 print(&amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;) Due to this, I ask that you ensure that if you follow any of my posts related to hacking you are doing it on your own equipment or equipment that you have prior permission to hack.</description></item></channel></rss>